Joshua Martínez

Website: https://mynjj.github.io

Profile

Hardworking passionate profesional, currently studying a Msc. in Computer Science. With experience in software development, which taught me to translate my hard-skills to useful products. Highly responsible on my work. Excited to learn more, try new things, face challenges, and to help.

EDUCATION

IT University Master of Science in Computer Science	Copenhaguen, Denmark Aug. 2020 – Present
• Universidad La Salle • Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communications; GPA: 4 (9.76/10.0)	Mexico City, Mexico Aug. 2012 – Nov. 2016
• Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México Bachelor of Mathematics	Mexico City, Mexico Aug. 2014 – Jul. 2018
Experience	
TIDE Software Engineer	Mexico City, Mexico Jan. 2019 - Aug. 2020

I developed many useful skills, learned to deliver fully functional products and to take responsability for them as a team. Designed and implemented creative solutions with several technologies.

- Employee time clock: Raspberry Pi's with multiple identification and synchronization features. Integrated sensors SDK's (C/Java), implemented features for the main service (Node.js), and UI(React)
- Airport Lounge app: Android/iOS app with React Native. Several features, integrated to an existing backend and created a backend-for-frontend for other features (Node.js/sails.js). Other technologies used: Redux, Firebase FCM
- o **Scotiabank's online pride parade**: Basic MMORPG for 2020's stay@home Pride Parade. AWS/EC2 instances running a Phaser.js game, connecting to WebSocket servers (Typescript). Redis used for chat features.
- IOT devices monitor: Utilities to provide software updates, remote SSH access and stats recopilation for remote technical support. Implemented features on both sides (Node.js, PHP/Symfony, React, Linux scripting).
- Coca-cola promotional game: Soccer game for marketing stands of Coca-cola running on Raspberry Pi's, controlled by a Wii controller. Created with Python/Pygame.
- Airport Lounge software: Software spanning several company areas. Implemented several features, on both backend (PHP/Symfony) and frontend (React/Redux).
- Restaurant software: Highly customized restaurant software. Implemented several features, on both backend (PHP/Symfony) and frontend (React/Redux).

VtSoftware

Software Engineer

Playa del Carmen, Mexico Jun. 2017 - May 2018

Email: djoshuamartinezpineda@gmail.com

I learned how to translate my academic knowledge to useful software. One of the most important skills I learned is to listen to the client requirements and design accordingly.

- Vacation Clubs Payroll Software: Modeled and designed according to customer needs. Bootstraped project on PHP/Laravel and Vue.js, integrated to an existing sales system DB. Also wrote some SQLServer stored procedures.
- **Hotel Inventory Software**: Modeled and designed according to customer needs. Bootstraped project on PHP/Laravel and jQuery.

École de Technologie Supérieure

 $Research\ Internship$

Montreal, Canada Apr. 2015 - Jul. 2015

• Estimation of disparity on GPUs: Research on disparity estimation algorithms and implementation on Matlab and then using C/CUDA

OTHER EXPERIENCE

• Teaching activities: Private tutor on mathematics and programming, mostly focusing on kids (from 9 to 16). Social Service as an English teacher for adults.

ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

- ANFEI's award: Highest GPA on engineering faculty. Graduated with Magna Cum Laude.
- Robotics Winter School. 2013: INAOE, Puebla, Mexico.
- Robotics competitions. 2011 2013: Participation on Robocup competitions with the school robotics team. Istanbul, Turkey and Mexico City.
- **Programming competitions.**: IEEExtreme Programming competitions.

SKILLS I'VE WORKED WITH

The state of the workers with	
LANGUAGES	L'ECHNOLOGIES
JS, TS, Node.js, Python, C, Java, SQL, PHP, Matlab	• Frontend:: React, Redux, React Native, Vue.js, Phaser, eCharts.
	• Backend:: Laravel, Symfony, Redis, Socket.io, Express, Sails.js
	• Other:: Linux, Raspberry Pi, AWS, Git, SVN, Nginx

OTHER SKILLS

 $\mathrm{C}++,$ Microchip PIC Assembler, Arduino, Eagle.